Gaurav Singh

Software Consultant UI

Having 3+ years of proven experience in developing Web Applications using different technologies. Effective in analyzing relevant information and guiding the product cycle from conception to completion. Looking forward to leveraging my knowledge and skills in the domain of Data Analytics and put that to the best of their use and excel at what I do.

🔀 gaurav.masand09@gmail.com



8217727225



Ghaziabad, India



in linkedin.com/in/singhgaurav09

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Consultant Knoldus Inc.

02/2021 - 01/2022

Noida,India

Responsibilities

- Handle a few projects independently, including requirement gathering, software architecture, development, unit testing, deploying to the production server, project closedown.
- Coordinate with clients, developers, and testers of complex projects during the entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- Work on several coding individual programs.
- Peer code reviews and carry out technical root cause
- Integrated Payment Gateway for Paytm, PayPal, Razor Pay.

Software Engineer IgluLabs Software Pvt. Ltd

06/2018 - 12/2020

Bangalore,India

Responsibilities

- Perform low to medium complexity source code development.
- Test software in controlled, real situations before it goes live.
- Built Responsive design using Bootstrap, CSS FlexBox, CSS
- Performing low to medium complexity source code development.
- Participated in scrum and sprint meetings. Performing unit testing on module as well.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

Sambhram Institute of Technology

08/2012 - 08/2016

59 5

12th Grade

Kendriya Vidyalaya, No.2, Jalahalli East

66.6 %

10th Grade

Kendriya Vidyalaya, No.2, Jalahalli East

2009 - 2010 8.6 CGPA

SKILLS



PROJECTS

55Rush (02/2021 - Present)

- Building WebApp for building online Canadian communities.
- Create valuable connections between members and our brand
- Technology used: Angular 11, Angular Material, Tailwind Css.

Rentsher

- Rentsher is a product, who provides rent to customers by communicating with the vendors.
- Technology used: Angular 9, HTML 5, Bootstrap 4.

Alumni Portal

- A Global Alumni Community to help Applicants gain insights into Careers, Universities, Student Life & more.
- Technology used: Angular 7, HTML 5, Bootstrap 4.

- Way cool is India's fastest growing online food distribution company, with a Network of 35000 farmers across fruits, vegetables, rice, pulses, and dairy products.
- Technology used: Angular 4/7, HTML 5, Bootstrap 4.

Pragati Direct

- Pragati Direct is a product that works as an agent between wholesalers and Kirana stores.
- Technology used: Angular 4/7, HTML 5, Bootstrap 4.

Castrol Smart Value

- Castrol Smart Value calculates the visual and graphical differences between Castrol products and other products in different fields.
- Technology used: Angular Js, HTML 5, Bootstrap 4.

LANGUAGES

Professional Working Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency